<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="c_psdk_android_subscribe-custom-tags"> 
  <title>Custom tags</title> 
  <shortdesc>Media streams can carry additional metadata in the form of tags in the
		playlist/manifest file, and this file indicates the placement of advertising. You can
		specify custom tag names and be notified when certain tags appear in the manifest file. </shortdesc> 
  <conbody> 
	 <section id="section_E99299152089418FBA56F5F09FC547B0"> 
		<title>HLS content tags</title> 
		<note type="important">This feature is not available for Safari on Apple
		  computers, because 
		  <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> uses the video tag, rather
		  than Flash or MSE, to play HLS content. 
		</note> 
		<p><ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> provides out-of-the-box
		  support for specific #EXT advertising tags. Your application can use custom
		  tags to enhance the advertising workflow or to support blackout scenarios. To
		  support advanced workflows, 
		  <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> allows you to specify and
		  subscribe to additional tags in the manifest. You can be notified when these
		  tags appear in the manifest file. 
		</p> 
		<note type="tip">You can subscribe to custom tags both for VOD and
		  live/linear streams. 
		</note> 
		<note type="other" othertype="Limitation">When HLS is played by using the <codeph>Video</codeph>
				tag in Safari, and not by using Flash Fallback, this feature will not be available
				in Safari. </note> 
	 </section> 
	 <section id="section_AD032318AEF5418393D2B1DF36B0BABB"> 
		<title>Using custom HLS tags</title> 
		<p>Here is an example of a customized VOD asset: 
		</p> 
		<codeblock>#EXTM3U
#EXT-X-VERSION:3
#EXT-X-TARGETDURATION:7
 
#EXT-X-ASSET:AID=10
 
#EXTINF:9.9766,
seg1.ts
 
#EXTINF:9.9766,
seg2.ts
 
#EXTINF:9.9766,
seg3.ts
 
#EXT-X-AD:DURATION=10
#EXTINF:9.9766,
seg4.ts
 
#EXTINF:9.9766,
seg5.ts
 
#EXT-X-ENDLIST</codeblock> 
		<p>Your application can set up the following scenarios: 
		</p> 
		<ul id="ul_6D4B0E5F269047CF9A70249D7B771995"> 
		  <li id="li_4B591E79A49B482C88C80A9D7BEBC18A">A notification when 
			 <codeph>#EXT-X-ASSET</codeph> tags, or any other set of custom tag
			 names to which you have subscribed, exist in the file. 
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_F9A306443020436F8A10B23A771DB543">Insert ads when an 
			 <codeph>#EXT-X-AD</codeph> tag, or any other custom tag name, is
			 found in the stream. 
		  </li> 
		</ul> 
		<p>You can subscribe to any of the following tags as custom tags: 
		  <codeph>EXT-PROGRAM-DATE-TIME</codeph>, 
		  <codeph>EXT-X-START</codeph>, 
		  <codeph>EXT-X-AD</codeph>, 
		  <codeph>EXT-X-CUE</codeph>, 
		  <codeph>EXT-X-ENDLIST</codeph>. You are notified with a 
		  <codeph>TimedMetadata</codeph> event during parsing of manifest files. 
		</p> 
		<p>There are some advertising tags, such as 
		  <codeph>EXT-X-CUE</codeph>, to which you are already subscribed. These
		  ad tags are also used by the default opportunity generator. You can specify
		  which ad tags are used by the default opportunity generator by setting the 
		  <codeph>adTags</codeph> property. 
		</p> 
	 </section> 
  </conbody> 
</concept> 
