<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="failover-missing-playlist"
 xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"> 
  <title>Missing playlist failover</title> 
  <shortdesc>When an entire playlist is missing, for example, when the M3U8
	 file that is specified in a top-level manifest file does not download, <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/>
	 attempts to recover. If it cannot be recovered, your application determines the
	 next step. 
  </shortdesc> 
  <conbody> 
	 <p>If the playlist that is associated with the middle-resolution bit rate is missing, <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/>
			searches for a variant playlist at the same resolution. If it finds the same resolution,
			<ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> starts downloading the variant playlist and the segments from the matching
			position. If the player does not find the same resolution playlist, it will try to cycle
			through other bitrate playlists and their variants. An immediately lower bitrate is the
			first choice, then its variant, and so on. If all of the lower bitrate playlists and
			their variants are exhausted in the attempt to find a valid playlist, <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> will go to
			the top bitrate and count down from there. If a valid playlist cannot be found, the
			process fails, and the player moves to the ERROR state. </p> 
	 <p>Your application can determine how to handle this situation. For example, you might want to
			close the player activity and direct the user to the catalog activity. The event of
			interest is the <codeph>STATUS_CHANGED</codeph> event, and the corresponding callback is
			the <codeph>onStatusChanged</codeph> method. Here is code that monitors whether the
			player changes its internal status to <codeph>ERROR</codeph>: </p> 
	 <codeblock outputclass="syntax java">...
case ERROR:
getActivity().finish(); // this is where we close the current activity (the Player activity)
break;
...</codeblock> 
  </conbody> 
</concept> 
