<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/reference.dtd">
<reference id="drm-overview-ref"
 xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"> 
  <title>Primetime DRM interface overview</title> 
  <shortdesc>The key client-side element of the Primetime digital rights management (DRM) system is
		the DRM Manager.  </shortdesc> 
  <refbody> 
	 <section id="section_4DD54E085AB345FE9BE00865E56B28DB"> 
		<p><ph conkeyref="phrases/drm-short"/> provides a scalable, efficient workflow to implement
				content protection in <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> applications. You
				protect and manage the rights to your video content by creating a license for each
				digital media file. </p> 
		<p><ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> supports <ph conkeyref="phrases/drm-short"/>
				integration as custom DRM workflows. This means that your application must implement
				the DRM authentication workflows before playing the stream by using the Flash
				DRMManager. To enable this, the MediaPlayer provides you with the DRM manager for
				authentication. </p> 
		<p > Refer to the DRM sample player code included
		  in the 
		  <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> package. 
		</p> 
		<p>These are the most important API elements for working with DRM: 
		<ul id="ul_DBC56B4C422B4190B95AC9629C170A90"> 
		  <li id="li_782BDA8121F04C9596779280C0953A7B"> 
			 <p>A reference in the media player to the DRM manager object that implements the DRM subsystem:
							<codeblock outputclass="synax objective-c">@property (readonly, nonatomic) DRMManager *drmManager</codeblock>
						</p> 
		  </li> 
		</ul> 
		</p> 
	 </section> 
	 <section id="section_F986DB1EDD6F44CD8E57419CCA0921E8">
			<p><ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> issues a
					<codeph>PTMediaPlayerItemDRMMetadataChanged</codeph> notification when the DRM
				metadata changes. This metadata is used as input for almost all functions of the
					<codeph>DRMManager</codeph> class. </p>
		</section> 
	 <section  id="section_223DCF63BAB6438792A85352A79044CC"> 
		<p>If the DRM-protected stream is multiple bit-rate (MBR) encoded, the
		  DRM metadata that is used for the variant playlist should be the same as the
		  metadata that is used in all the bit-rate streams. 
		</p> 
		<note importance="high" type="tip">When referencing DRM-protected asset
		  URLs in your iOS app, the query string parameter 
		  <codeph>?faxs=1</codeph> must be appended to the (MBR) set-level M3U8
		  URL. For example: 
		  <codeblock outputclass="syntax html">https://your.domain.com/hls/[...]/index.m3u8?faxs=1</codeblock>The 
		  <codeph>faxs=1</codeph> query string parameter signals that the content
		  is DRM protected, and triggers the DRM decryption workflow accordingly in the
		  iOS 
		  <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/>. You can also append the 
		  <codeph>faxs=1</codeph> tag on DRM-protected HLS asset URLs that are
		  destined for other platforms; it is observed as required on iOS or treated as a
		  non-op in players on other platforms. 
		</note> 
	 </section> 
	 <section id="section_F58941D68EB94A5EBD1C7454D2A1B17A"> 
		<p>For more information about DRM, see the <xref href="http://help.adobe.com/en_US/primetime/drm"
					format="html" scope="external">
					<ph conkeyref="phrases/drm-long"/> documentation</xref>. </p> 
	 </section> 
  </refbody> 
</reference> 
