<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="trick_play_limitations"> 
  <title>Limitations and behavior for trick play</title> 
  <shortdesc>There are some limitations and some issues in the way trick play
	 mode behaves. 
  </shortdesc> 
  <conbody> 
	 <section id="section_30B7A1C0F63E45A59CEFCDFB3FDD67F8"> 
		<p >Here are the limitations for trick play mode: 
		<ul id="ul_525AC8E8150F4A4A80E7C36B4C7C4E28"> 
		  <li id="li_2B0AE11DFF0549AE8F8DE36ECAC2E228"> The master playlist must
			 contain I-frame-only segments. Only the key frames from the I-frame track are
			 displayed on the screen. 
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_47ED7C4EEF7F4AC18D923A187527FCE9">The audio track and closed
			 captions are disabled. 
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_42961CF0D305478184D881D5AC0C9510">Adaptive bit rate (ABR)
			 logic is disabled. 
			 <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> selects one bit rate
			 between the lowest provided rate and 800 kbps and uses that rate during the
			 entire trick-play session. 
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_E801656932C54CA9BA694083523EEA31">Play and pause are
			 enabled. 
		  </li>
		  <li id="li_1C947FC64EF4450E82207075E699F621">Seek is disallowed. To
			 seek, call 
			 <codeph>pause</codeph> to exit trick play mode and then call 
			 <codeph>seek</codeph>. 
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_C1ACBD41C73248519D7810B107F44813">You can exit trick-play
			 mode into any allowed playback rate (play or pause). 
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_63C8D96A432A486CBA65249E0F656391">When ads are incorporated in the stream: <ul
							id="ul_2DEB61B6FB5140B4822BD37E09566682">
							<li id="li_ECD1032478594EF4805F9678099E85F2">You can go to trick play
								only while playing the main content. An error is dispatched if you
								try to switch to trick play during an ad break. </li>
							<li id="li_D4DCC5BE4BC243DD81EC3FA0F1FAE1E1">After commencing trick play
								mode, ad breaks are ignored and no ad events are fired. </li>
							<li id="li_B1EF803DFC244C7FA210B1F308E7AFF1">The timeline exposed by <ph
									conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> to the player
								application is not modified even if ad breaks are skipped. </li>
							<li id="li_0036C10989434E078BAF29065EFC7646">The
									<codeph>MediaPlayer.currentTime</codeph> property jumps forward
								(on fast forward) or backward (on fast rewind) with the duration of
								the skipped ad break. This jump behavior for the current time allows
								the stream duration to remain unmodified during trick play. Your
								player application can use the <codeph>localTime</codeph> property
								to track the time relative only to the main content. No time jumps
								are performed on the values returned for the local time when
								skipping an ad. </li>
							<li id="li_D9C3A9033C4D4F199C145B51B6D08CC4">The
									<codeph>AdBreakPlaybackEvent.AD_BREAK_SKIPPED</codeph> event is
								dispatched immediately before an ad break is about to be skipped.
								Your player can use this event to implement custom logic related to
								the skipped ad breaks. </li>
							<li id="li_6EDBAAF091114D93AEF23C049FFF7BC4">Exiting trick play invokes
								the same ad playback policy as when exiting seek. <p>Therefore, as
									in seeking, the behavior depends on whether your application's
									playback policy is different from the default. The default is
									that the last skipped ad break is played at the point where you
									come out of trick play. </p></li>
						</ul></li> 
		</ul> 
		</p> 
	 </section> 
  </conbody> 
</concept> 
