<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="c_psdk_android_failover-missing-segment"
 xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"> 
  <title>Missing segment failover</title> 
  <shortdesc>When a segment is missing, for example when a particular segment fails to download, <ph
			conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> attempts to recover through a variety of
		failover attempts. If it cannot recover, it issues an error.  </shortdesc> 
  <conbody> 
	 <p>If a segment is missing on the server because, for example, the manifest
	 	file is not present, the segment cannot be downloaded, and so on, 
	 	<ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/>
		attempts to fail over by trying the following options: 
	 </p> 
	 <ol> 
		<li>Attempt a failover to the same segment, at the same bit rate, in a variant file.</li> 
		<li>Switch to an alternate bit rate (ABR switch) in the same file.</li> 
		<li>Cycle through every available bit rate in every available variant.</li> 
		<li>Skip the segment and issue a warning.</li> 
	 </ol> 
  	<p>When <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> cannot obtain an alternative segment, it
			triggers a <codeph>CONTENT_ERROR</codeph> error notification. This notification contains
			an inner notification with the code <codeph>DOWNLOAD_ERROR</codeph> code. If the stream
			with the problem is an alternate audio track, <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"
			/> generates the <codeph>AUDIO_TRACK_ERROR</codeph> error notification. </p> 
	 <p>If the video engine is continuously unable to obtain segments, it limits continuous segment
			skips to 5, after which playback is stopped and <ph
				conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> issues a <codeph>NATIVE_ERROR</codeph> with
			the code 5. </p> 
	 <note type="restriction">
		<p>The adaptive bit rate (ABR) control parameters are not taken into consideration 
		   when a failover occurs. This is because the failover mechanism is designed to use any of the 
		   currently available playlists, regardless of their bit-rate profile, as backup streams. 
		</p>
		<p>During a failover operation, there can be a profile switch. If an
		  error occurs during the download of one of the playlist segments, ABR control
		  parameters such as min/max allowed bit rate are ignored. 
		</p>
	 </note> 
  </conbody> 
</concept> 
