<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="ad-markers-add-custom"
 xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"> 
  <title>Add custom ad markers</title> 
  <shortdesc>By using custom ad markers, you can mark specific sections of the
	 main content as ad-related content periods. 
  </shortdesc> 
  <conbody> 
	 <p>This feature is most useful when content is being recorded, for example,
		from a live event, and the result of the recording is one HLS stream. The
		recording contains the main content and advertising-related content in one HLS
		video-on-demand (VOD) stream. The recording process does not keep track of the
		ad-related segments, so the information that is related to the positioning of
		the ads in the main content is lost. 
	 </p> 
	 <p>You might be able to obtain the information that is related to the
		positioning of the ad-content periods from other out-of-band sources, such as
		external CMS systems. You can define custom markers, through which this
		out-of-band information can be passed to the timeline manager subsystem. The
		intention is to mark the content sections that match the specified ad-related
		content in such a way that all ad-specific playback events are triggered in the
		same manner as if these custom ad-periods were explicitly placed on the
		player's timeline. 
	 </p> 
	 <p>Ad tracking is not handled internally by <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/>, such as when ads are
		resolved by 
		<ph conkeyref="phrases/auditude-name-long"/>. However, <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> provides the
		following abstractions that define the way ad-related content is represented on
		the timeline: 
	 <ul id="ul_6DD0EAFD2FE04C25BB3D0503A82C56D0"> 
		<li id="li_DB141DCF90B74B25A48E7EE502934BC4">The ad break 
		  <p>An ad break is an ordered list of individual consecutive ads. 
		  </p> 
		</li> 
		<li id="li_606E6BB20CFF4099A64C60DB21449468">An individual ad 
		</li> 
	 </ul> 
	 </p> 
	 <p>Playback events are triggered separately for ad breaks and ads at the
		start and end point for each ad. 
	 </p> 
	 <p><ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> dispatches ad tracking events to your application, so you can
		implement your own tracking logic. If you set custom ad markers, you receive
		the 
		<codeph>onAdBreakStart</codeph>, 
		<codeph>onAdStart</codeph>, 
		<codeph>onAdProgress</codeph>, 
		<codeph>onAdComplete</codeph>, and 
		<codeph>onAdBreakComplete</codeph> events. 
	 </p> 
  </conbody> 
</concept> 
