<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="trick_play_limitations"> 
  <title>Limitations and behavior for trick play</title> 
  <shortdesc>
  </shortdesc> 
  <conbody> 
	 <section id="section_2BC43539C5C142E085D06A7E35C76726"> 
		<p>Limitations for trick play mode: <ul id="ul_B3128162E1904FEB936C74FD6C3AA8FB">
					<li id="li_F64738253C99416C9A0F3864DF30A0AC">The master playlist must contain
						Iframe-only segments. <p>Only the key frames from the Iframe track are
							displayed on the screen. </p>
					</li>
					<li id="li_A2D0AFAC0E81482B9E55D6D07A4FE4A8">The audio track and closed captions
						are disabled. </li>
					<li id="li_52549784321746B78E1968E67DEEEED7">Play and pause are enabled. </li>
					<li id="li_72DB0C47A34348318CA1985F0216C5B5">You can exit trick-play mode into
						any allowed playback rate (play or pause). </li>
					<li id="li_E95DFD620C1F4BECAB28013D08A9EEA6">When ads are incorporated in the
						stream: <ul id="ul_F50CB8F9372D45A28A8615B4008AF30E">
							<li id="li_BC955034837944E58A8F19D7E91E1C72">You can go to trick play
								only while playing the main content. An error is dispatched if you
								try to switch to trick play during an ad break. </li>
							<li id="li_AE47539F2FC04209AEFFB5FBFDBC0A5D">After starting trick play
								mode, ad breaks are ignored and no ad events are fired. </li>
							<li id="li_A01783D462054240A2B3C00BA33B1544">The timeline exposed by <ph
									conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> to the player is not
								modified even if ad breaks are skipped. </li>
							<li id="li_78745E8617174F16A285052B54D485E3">The current time value
								jumps forward (on fast forward) or backward (on fast rewind) with
								the duration of the skipped ad break. <p>This jump behavior for the
									current time allows the stream duration to remain unmodified
									during trick play. Your player can track the time relative only
									to the main content. No time jumps are performed on the values
									returned for the local time when skipping an ad. </p>
							</li>
							<li id="li_D7231E91DBB04DCBBA99EDAFC67C2AED">The
									<codeph>MediaPlayerEvent.AD_BREAK_SKIPPED</codeph> event is
								dispatched immediately before an ad break is about to be skipped.
									<p>Your player can use this event to implement custom logic
									related to the skipped ad breaks. </p>
							</li>
							<li id="li_8F9292AED93142B9B575AE2ECFAFF0B3">Exiting trick play invokes
								the same ad playback policy as when exiting seek. <p>As with
									seeking, the behavior depends on whether your application's
									playback policy is different from the default. The default is
									that the last skipped ad break is played at the point where you
									come out of trick play. </p>
							</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p> 
	 </section> 
  </conbody> 
</concept> 
