<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="c_psdk_ad-transcoding"
 xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"> 
  <title>Repackage incompatible ads using Adobe Creative Repackaging Service (CRS)</title> 
  <shortdesc> Some third-party ads (or creatives) cannot be stitched into the HTTP Live Streaming
		(HLS) content stream because their video format is incompatible with HLS. <ph
			conkeyref="phrases/ad-insert-name"/> and <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> can optionally attempt to repackage
		incompatible ads into compatible M3U8 videos. </shortdesc> 
  <conbody> 
	 <p>Ads served from various third parties, such as an agency ad server, your
		inventory partner, or an ad network, are often delivered in incompatible
		formats, such as the progressive download MP4 format. 
	 </p> 
	 <p>When <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> first encounters an incompatible ad, the player ignores the ad and issues a request
			to the <ph conkeyref="phrases/crs-name"/> (<ph conkeyref="phrases/crs-acronym"/>), which
			is part of the <ph conkeyref="phrases/ad-insert-name"/> back end, to repackage the ad
			into a compatible format. <ph conkeyref="phrases/crs-acronym"/> attempts to generate
			multiple bit rate M3U8 renditions of the ad and stores these renditions on the Primetime
			Content Delivery Network (CDN). The next time <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> receives an ad response that points
			to that ad, the player uses the HLS-compatible M3U8 version from the CDN. </p> 
	 <p>To activate this optional CRS feature, contact your Adobe representative. <note>For <ph
					conkeyref="phrases/crs-acronym"/> Version 3.0 (and earlier) customers, beginning
				with <ph conkeyref="phrases/crs-acronym"/> Version 3.1 the following changes have
				improved both security and performance: <ul id="ul_nky_gwb_mz">
					<li><ph conkeyref="phrases/crs-acronym"/> 3.1 continues with
							<codeph>https:</codeph> if the content being repackaged uses
							<codeph>https:</codeph>. This reduces the potential for some players to
						present unsecure content.</li>
					<li><ph conkeyref="phrases/crs-acronym"/> 3.1 greatly minimizes network calls,
						improving video startup time.</li>
				</ul>
			</note></p> 
	 <p>For more information about CRS, see 
		<xref href="http://help.adobe.com/en_US/primetime/crs/index.html"
		 format="html" scope="external">Creative Packaging Service (CRS)</xref>. 
	 </p> 
  </conbody> 
</concept> 
