<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_abr-for-quality"> 
  <title>Adaptive bit rates (ABR) for video quality</title> 
  <shortdesc> HLS and DASH streams provide different bit rate encodings (profiles) for the same
		short burst of video. <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> can select the quality
		level for each burst based on the available bandwidth. </shortdesc> 
  <conbody> 
	 <p> 
		<ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> constantly monitors the bit
		rate to ensure that the content is played at the optimal bit rate for the
		current network connection. 
	 </p> 
	 <p> You can set the adaptive bit-rate (ABR) switching policy and the
		initial, minimum, and maximum bit rates for a multiple-bit-rate (MBR) stream. 
		<ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> automatically switches to
		the bit rate that provides the best playback experience in the specified
		configuration. 
	 </p> 
	 <table id="table_AF838E082235406AA359BF1C1A77F85F"> 
		<tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="col01" colnum="1"
		  colwidth="1.00*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="3.45*"/> 
		  <tbody> 
			 <row> 
				<entry colname="col01">Initial bit rate 
				</entry> 
				<entry colname="col2">
				  <p>The desired playback bit rate (in bits per second) for the
					 first segment. When playback starts, the closest profile, which is equal to or
					 greater than the initial bit rate, is used for the first segment. 
				  </p>
				  <p> If a minimum bit rate is defined, and the initial bit rate is
					 lower than the minimum rate, 
					 <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> selects the
					 profile with the lowest bit rate above the minimum bit rate. If the initial
					 rate is above the maximum rate, 
					 <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> selects the
					 highest rate below the maximum rate. 
				  </p> 
				  <p>If the initial bit rate is zero or undefined, the initial bit
					 rate is determined by the ABR policy. 
				  </p> 
				</entry> 
			 </row> 
			 <row> 
				<entry colname="col01">Minimum bit rate 
				</entry> 
				<entry colname="col2">
				  <p>The lowest allowed bit rate to which the ABR can switch. ABR
					 switching ignores profiles with a bit rate that is lower than this bit rate. 
				  </p> 
				</entry> 
			 </row> 
			 <row> 
				<entry colname="col01">Maximum bit rate 
				</entry> 
				<entry colname="col2">
				  <p>The highest allowed bit rate to which the ABR can switch. ABR
					 switching ignores profiles with a bit rate higher than this bit rate. 
				  </p> 
				</entry> 
			 </row> 
		  </tbody> 
		</tgroup> 
	 </table> 
	 <p>Keep the following information in mind: 
	 <ul id="ul_05F3B92E1B524782B317502383D3A68A">
		<li 
		 id="li_C3C0992410FC45B6B49DAFFD4944DE97"><ph
		  conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> does not dispatch events from bit-rate
		  switching. 
		</li>
		<li id="li_35B1808E70234C8F87DD72871C224E3C">You can change your ABR
		  settings at any time, and the player switches to use the profile that most
		  closely matches the most recent settings. 
		</li> 
	 </ul> 
	 </p> 
	 <p>For example, if a stream has the following profiles: <ul
				id="ul_6A5A6684626F409BBE96E536500477FC">
				<li id="li_88049490AD4247A8BE4A76105BE3305F">1: 300000 </li>
				<li id="li_F2506EBEC4B84822ABA314FE1538F866">2: 700000 </li>
				<li id="li_BCC6400E5369447D9486E7F6E8268EFE">3: 1500000 </li>
				<li id="li_A29AC860B8374611984199461BB8C7C2">4: 2400000 </li>
				<li id="li_32AE98C8B3DF4E5EB7603B11E26D753E">5: 4000000 </li>
			</ul> If you specify a range of 300000 to 2000000, <ph
				conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> considers only profiles 1, 2 and 3. This
			allows applications to adjust to various network conditions, such as switching from WiFi
			to 3G or to various devices such as a phone, a tablet, or a desktop computer. </p> 
  </conbody> 
</concept> 
