<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="render.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_ufj_jct_wy"> 
  <title>Ad measurements from Moat</title> 
  <shortdesc>TVSDK takes information from FreeWheel and other ad servers providing VAST responses.
		FreeWheel provides, within VAST responses, information from the Moat service. The Moat
		service counts ad impressions with an accuracy that better shows whether creatives capture
		or neglect an audience's interests. </shortdesc> 
  <conbody> 
	 <p>Moat is a service measuring ad viewing across many uses, from browsers
		to within applications. Moat generates marketing analytics data in real-time
		across multiple platforms. 
	 </p> 
	 <p>The VAST response XML has a property and an element your code can read, the outermost
				<codeph>Ad id</codeph> property and the outermost <codeph>Extension</codeph>
			element. Either way, your code can use TVSDK to save both the <codeph>Ad id</codeph>
			information and the <codeph>Extension</codeph> information, then organize the
			information in a tree structure. With this organization, your code can pick up the data
			from any level and pass it along to wherever it needs to go. The value of the outermost
				<codeph>Ad id</codeph> property enables your code to coordinate information from the
			associated campaign. </p> 
	 <p>For example, FreeWheel can return data in an Extensions element. Below
		is a sample element. 
	 </p> 
	 <codeblock outputclass="syntax xml">&lt;?xml version="1.0"?>
&lt;Extensions>
  &lt;Extension type="FreeWheel">
    &lt;Parameter name="moat">
      &lt;MeasurementInfo renditionID="6398737" type="MediaFile">
        &lt;MoatID>&lt;![CDATA[169843;56705;17860255;17860316;2509639;g8912342;103311138;g436558;530633]]&gt;&lt;/MoatID>
      &lt;/MeasurementInfo>
      &lt;MeasurementInfo renditionID="6398739" type="MediaFile">
        &lt;MoatID>&lt;![CDATA[169843;56705;17860255;17860316;2509639;g8912342;103311138;g436558;530633]]&gt;&lt;/MoatID>
      &lt;/MeasurementInfo>
    &lt;/Parameter>
  &lt;/Extension>
&lt;/Extensions>
</codeblock> 
	 <p>Freewheel can also set the <codeph>id</codeph> property in the <codeph>Ad</codeph> element, as
			shown in the sample below. </p> 
	 <codeblock outputclass="syntax xml">&lt;Ad id="118566" sequence="1"&gt;</codeblock> 
	 <p>Refer to the API documentation for the class <codeph>NetworkAdInfo</codeph>.</p> 
  </conbody>
</concept>
