<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="c_psdk_stagevideo-capabilities"> 
  <title>StageVideo capabilities and restrictions</title> 
  <shortdesc>On devices that support GPU (hardware) acceleration, you can use a
			<codeph>flash.media.StageVideo</codeph> object to process video on the device hardware.
		The availability of <codeph>StageVideo</codeph> depends upon the versions and capabilities
		of different parts of your system including Flash Player, video hardware, OS, drivers,
		browser, network connection, and viewing context.  </shortdesc> 
  <conbody> 
	 <p>The <codeph>StageVideo</codeph> class lets you take advantage of hardware acceleration to
			present video at the highest possible performance level for a device. The availability
			and performance of <codeph>StageVideo</codeph> is affected by the following factors: </p> 
	 <ul id="ul_gfl_bwd_jp"> 
		<li id="li_18860246328545328B8BBA8CDC275602"><b>Hardware acceleration</b> - When hardware
				acceleration is available, <codeph>StageVideo</codeph> processes video on the device
				hardware. When hardware acceleration is not available, the
					<codeph>StageVideo</codeph> responds depends on which version of Flash you are
				running: <ul id="ul_ah2_g32_jp">
					<li id="li_E5D70C91C596428CA5F5C373AD39E068"><i>Flash 15 and later</i> - When
						hardware acceleration is not available, <codeph>StageVideo</codeph> falls
						back to software, and you do not have to do anything. <note type="tip">When
							hardware acceleration is not available, performance can degrade
							significantly. </note>
					</li>
					<li id="li_B527D1011478416BB90408142E9A8478"><i>Flash 14 and earlier</i> - When
						hardware acceleration is not available, <codeph>StageVideo</codeph> becomes
						unavailable. In a small set of configurations where hardware acceleration is
						not supported by the browser or GPU, or is turned off in the Flash Player,
						video display with the <ph
							conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"
							><?xm-replace_text Phrase?></ph> HLS stack will fail. In the <i>HDS</i>
						pipeline, you can switch from <codeph>StageVideo</codeph> to an alternate,
						such as the Video object, that processes video in the CPU. </li>
				</ul>
			</li> 
		<li id="li_E73EC505D61449DEAA331474222EEFC1"><b>Presentation context</b> - During full screen
				viewing, <codeph>StageVideo</codeph> is always available and performance will be at
				the maximum level that is available on the device. When not viewing full-screen, the
				video presentation falls under the context of the browser, where the browser's
				settings and capabilities are used. </li> 
		<li id="li_11550F5173DB499D957D61F73C7012FD"><b>wmode</b> - In the browser context, the
					<codeph>wmode</codeph> setting is critical to performance. Adobe recommends that
				you keep <codeph>wmode</codeph> set to <codeph>direct</codeph> to ensure the best
				possible performance in the browser context. <note type="remember">The combination
					of factors that include <codeph>wmode</codeph>, <codeph>StageVideo</codeph>, and
					Flash result in different capabilities and restrictions, depending upon how fast
					your hardware runs and which version of Flash you are using. </note>
				<ul id="ul_ql5_hb2_jp">
					<li id="li_C650046B6A6049AFA07A813B62695170"><i>Flash 15 and later</i> -
							<codeph>StageVideo</codeph> is available with all available
							<codeph>wmode</codeph> settings. However, if you set
							<codeph>wmode</codeph> to a setting other than <codeph>direct</codeph>,
						performance will be lower. </li>
					<li id="li_4ECA09800CAC40D0869323487649B07C"><i>Flash 14 and earlier</i> - If
						you set <codeph>wmode</codeph> to a setting other than
							<codeph>direct</codeph>, <codeph>StageVideo</codeph> is not available in
						all browsers. </li>
				</ul>
			</li> 
	 </ul> 
  </conbody> 
</concept> 
