<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="c_psdk_stage-video-flash15-support"> 
  <title>Flash 15 support for StageVideo</title> 
  <shortdesc>From Flash 15 and later, when hardware rendering with StageVideo
	 is not available, StageVideo seamlessly falls back to a software StageVideo
	 object.
  </shortdesc> 
  <conbody> 
	 <p>Consider the following information about the Flash 15 StageVideo
		fallback to software:
	 <ul id="ul_ihy_qxk_gp"> 
		<li id="li_8B0233D6615A48808D5A9ADEB31886DA">No code changes are required
		  in your application.
		</li> 
		<li id="li_ADB306D1E4A94EBBBC78210B9642AE77">No change to the <ph
						conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"
						><?xm-replace_text Phrase?></ph> is required. <p>You do not need a <ph
							conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"
							><?xm-replace_text Phrase?></ph> update to use StageVideo fallback to
						software. </p>
				</li> 
		<li id="li_1DD139DA6CE349238E7C15DA0601A8E0">Your applications need to be
		  recompiled for Flash 15.
		</li> 
		<li id="li_AC3B42EF9308486496175CD9DE5115AB">Applications that you
		  recompile for Flash 15 will continue to work with Flash 14 and earlier, as long
		  as these applications do not use any new APIs that were introduced in Flash
		  Player 15. 
		  <p>If your Flash 14 application needs to use a new Flash 15 API, you
			 must dynamically call the API with a cast to the Object type, so that the
			 application does not fail in Flash Player 14 at runtime.
		  </p>
		</li> 
	 </ul> 
	 </p> 
	 <p><b>HTML Overlays 
		</b>
	 </p> 
	 <p>In Flash 15 and later, you can maintain a seamless display of HTML
		overlays when hardware StageVideo becomes unavailable and falls back to
		software StageVideo. To enable this feature, set 
		<codeph>wmode=opaque</codeph>.
	 </p> 
	 <p>Some older browsers do not support hardware acceleration. For more information about these
			requirements, see <xref
				href="r_psdk_dhls_1.4_requirements-stage-video.xml#reference_req_stagevideo"
				format="dita" scope="local"
				><?xm-replace_text StageVideo minimum requirements?></xref>. When you set
				<codeph>wmode=opaque</codeph>, the video is rendered with software StageVideo, which
			can impact performance. Typically, setting <codeph>wmode=direct</codeph> directly
			renders video to GPU, which results in much better performance. However, this option
			also overrides HTML overlays. </p> 
  </conbody> 
</concept> 
