<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/reference.dtd">
<reference id="mediaplayer-mediaresource-classes"
 xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"> 
  <title>MediaPlayer and MediaResource classes</title> 
  <shortdesc>A MediaResource represents the content that is about to be loaded by the
			<codeph>MediaPlayer</codeph> instance. </shortdesc> 
  <refbody> 
	 <section id="section_B09A012C97454AF58CE2269B800D8027"> 
		<p>The <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/> library provides a simple means to load and
				prepare content for playback by using the <codeph>replaceCurrentResource</codeph>
				method in the <codeph>MediaPlayer</codeph> interface. This method receives an
				instance of the <codeph>MediaResource</codeph> class as the sole input argument. The
					<codeph>MediaResource</codeph> class is composed of the following information:
					<ul id="ul_2A87E1029566408488FF614D3E06AC5A">
					<li id="li_D46E894EA4B34D72B4DE5B60AD7C5FCB">A URL, which represents the
						location of the content that is about to be loaded. </li>
					<li id="li_C9770668C177432F840B10B96A5C3DE8">A type, which is the type of
						content that is about to be loaded. <p>This is a string that defines the
							types of content that can be loaded by the <codeph>MediaPlayer</codeph>.
							Possible values are HLS and HDS. Each value is associated with the
							string representing the file extensions commonly used, “m3u8” for HLS
							and “f4m” for HDS. </p>
					</li>
					<li id="li_621A17E8EDC54408B3CAEF2568756EFE">Some metadata, which is an instance
						of the <codeph>Metadata</codeph> class. <p>This dictionary-like structure
							might contain additional information about the content that is about to
							be loaded, such as information about the alternate/ad content that
							should be placed in the main content. </p>
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p> 
		<p>The metadata is the medium through which information that is related
		  to alternate content is passed to 
		  <ph conkeyref="phrases/primetime-sdk-name"/>. The 
		  <codeph>Metadata</codeph> interface defines the API for a generic
		  key-value store, where both the key and the value are plain strings. 
		</p> 
	 </section> 
  </refbody> 
</reference> 
