<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="task_nrt_w15_zr">
    <title>Configure Video Analytics</title>
    <shortdesc/>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>You can track video usage in the Primetime Android Reference Implementation by
                configuring it to work with your Adobe Analytics account. The Android Reference
                Implementation is designed to send video usage and heartbeat data to Adobe
                Analytics. To enable this feature, you must first contact your Adobe Primetime
                representative and create an Adobe Analytics account. </p>
            <p>There are two places within the Reference Implementation that you must configure to
                enable the Adobe Analytics integration. The run-time Video Analytics configurations
                take affect once a new video is selected for playback (i.e. once a new PlayerActiviy
                is created). </p>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>Configure load-time options in the <codeph>ADBMobileConfig.json</codeph> assets
                    file. </cmd>
                <info>This file is provided by your Adobe representative. It is not included in the
                    Primetime SDK bundle by default. For more information on the settings in this
                    config file, see the Android Programmer's Guide here:  <xref
                        href="http://help.adobe.com/en_US/primetime/psdk/android/index.html#PSDKs-task-Initialize_and_configure_video_analytics_"
                        format="html" scope="external">Initialize and configure video
                        analytics</xref>. </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Configure run-time options in the Reference Implementation settings menu</cmd>
                <info>
                    <fig id="fig_tfd_w3y_zr">
                        <title>Reference Implementation Video Analytics Settings Menu</title>
                        <image href="images/img_psdk_ref_impl_va-settings-menu.png"
                            id="image_itb_qjy_zr" placement="break" align="left"/>
                    </fig>
                    <table id="table_lsq_hg5_zr">
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Run-time Options</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Video Analytics tracking server</entry>
                                    <entry>URL of the video analytics back-end collection end-point.
                                        This is where all video heartbeat tracking calls are
                                        sent.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Job ID</entry>
                                    <entry>The processing job identifier. This indicates to the
                                        back-end endpoint which kind of processing to apply for the
                                        video-tracking calls.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Channel</entry>
                                    <entry>The name of the channel where the user is watching the
                                        content. For a mobile application, this is typically the
                                        name of the application.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Publisher</entry>
                                    <entry>The name of the content publisher</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Debug Logging</entry>
                                    <entry>Activates extensive logging. Disabled by default, this
                                        can impact performance when enabled, so you disable this for
                                        a production environment.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Quiet Mode</entry>
                                    <entry>When this is enabled, no network calls are made, so this
                                        would be useful for local debugging, but must be disabled
                                        for a production environment.</entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </info>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
